# MAURICIO GOMEZ BLANCO MBA, BSME, BSEE, PM, QM

8502 Edgewood Dr. Rowlett, TX 75089 +1 (305) 772.7449 / gomezb\_mauricio@hotmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Proven senior level Quality leader with outstanding record of Quality Management Systems, Supplier Quality Management, New product development, Engineering Management, Project Management, R&D, Quality Assurance, Operations Excellence, Strategic management, Manufacturing, Auditing, and 3<sup>rd</sup> Party certifications.

More than 25 years in different International and domestic assignments, collaborating and managing multi-functional and multicultural teams. Experience on Development of new products and technologies, implement and manage Quality systems, project execution, develop and partner with strategic suppliers.

Experience on following Industries: Consumer electronics, Automotive, Chemicals and Construction products (Fire Protection).

Self-motivated, results oriented, teamwork, excellence, continuous improvement, problem solving, analytical thinking, people development, strategy, self-awareness, constructive and collaborative.

#### **SKILLS & CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Quality Systems and Management
- Quality Strategy Development and Deployment
- Supplier Quality Management
- New Product Development
- Project & Program Management
- Business development and P&L
- Auditing and 3<sup>rd</sup> party approvals
- Quality Systems ISO9001, TS16941, AS9100
- Risk Management, AFMEA, DFMEA/PFMEA
- Manufacturing processes and Production Technologies

- Lean and Six Sigma
- Problem solving
- Regulatory and Compliance
- Change management
- -Team building and coaching
- Leadership & management
- APQP, PPAP, New Product launch
- Lead International & multicultural Teams
- Process redesign & continuous improvement
- SAP, ECTR, JIRA, Minitab, AI,

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Sr. Global Quality Manager, Hilti North America Inc. Irving Texas

June 2015- Present

- Quality lead for new product development, design, manufacturing, supplier quality, Quality Management System, configuration management, risk management and process improvement.
- Successfully developed and launched 23 new product lines, multiple game changing new products for Fire
  Protection significant accumulative revenue of \$1.5B usd for this business, responsible for quality of
  development, manufacturing, meeting testing approvals and regulations.
- Ensured strong implementation of Hilti North America new products to continue strengthening leadership in Fire Protection thanks to a solid pipeline of innovations; like metal deck application \$200M revenue.
- Responsible for Supplier Quality strategy development and implementation for North America and Europe.
- Evaluate, select, monitor and develop suppliers for our programs, implement long term development, targets, and supplier performance. Responsible for Quality contract for suppliers to develop strategic partnerships.
- Quality and development, design to manufacturing, APQP, Product reliability and increase customer satisfaction for new products and existing products in our portfolio, new products launched successful and robust Quality, zero customer complaints and providing proactive support.
- Responsible to support and provide guidance on regulatory and product safety requirements for Tools, firestop products, passive systems, construction code regulations.
- Risk analysis and risk mitigation measures, project, technical, quality, project execution and financial success.
- Lead cross functional team and improvements with on the design, manufacturing, suppliers, approvals, and customers key stakeholders to achieve Quality performance goals and strategy.
- Problem solving with to address voice of the customer, 8D, A3, 5-whys, etc. conduct diagnostic, implementing process, and design improvements.
- Working collaboratively with customers, internally and suppliers to create a quality culture with proven results of reducing customer issues and improving time to market reducing costs in highly regulated industries.
- Drive improvement, strategic initiatives Globally to be used by Quality teams, like Requirement Engineering, reduction Cost of Non-Quality, Quality of the development, improvement of product and processes, bringing strong contribution to the Organization to meet strategic goals, growth, and financial performance.
- Expert on turning problems into effective and functional opportunities fostering team enthusiasm and voice of the customer; knowledge transfer, risk mitigation, Failure Resolution Process to reduce warranty cost, increase quality, and improve customer satisfaction.
- Trained, mentor, sharing of best practices and lessons learned to new talents to achieve operational excellence and strategy.

### Quality & Engineering Manager IDQ Holdings, Inc / (Spectrum Brands)

June 2009- June 2015

- Developed, maintain, and continues improvement of a new Quality system that covers all aspects of incoming/ in-process and Outgoing Quality Control, to process refrigerant Gas; oil lubricants, sealing products & accessories, used for Automobile A/C systems.
- Developed Product KQC and product specifications, testing, reliability and performance for new products, raw materials, components, and finished goods.
- Supervise development, planning, and implementation of new products, mechanical design and reduction of design cycle time and costs while improving overall quality, product specifications, productivity, and reliability targets.
- Developed Engineering and Quality plans in line with the overall business plans, including new product development, Mechanical design, DFMEA, PFMEA, Testing validation and Part Approvals.
- Engineering design, regulatory compliance, and quality standards.
- Responsible to manage chemicals, formulation preparation for Oil lubricants, additives, and blends.
- Analyze field quality information, quality nonconformance, define root cause and implement corrective actions thru product design change, supplier quality improvements.
- Identify CTQ (Critical to Quality) product and process points, establishing convenient data collection practices to improve process and develop six sigma projects.

# Program Manager, DELPHI Automotive Systems

Feb 2004- Jun 2009

- Strategy and Launch Manager for design, manufacturing of Ignition and Smart Remotes Actuators, automotive product lines Powertrain.
- Direct customer contact on project development, implementation and final customer's quality approval for new products start of production, main OEM automotive customers.
- Responsible to plan manage and execution of engineering development projects from concept, development design, Quality, and product manufacturing on the Automotive Industry.
- Ensure on time derivable of projects key metrics timing, PPAP, cost & quality. Tracking of business case, %OI, IRR, NPV, profitability and meet projects budget.
- Responsible to coordinate activities to meet Quality performance, reliability, KPI, Productivity. APQP, Process
   Product System Design.
- Strong leadership, results oriented, lean used into projects execution in worldwide projects mainly located in Asia-Pacific, Europe & North America, coordinate activities between Customers, Suppliers, Technical Centers, and Manufacturing plants
- Establish sustainable solutions of customer-relevant requirements for new vehicle projects and platforms by utilizing internal and external resources

# Project Manager, Thomson Multimedia

Aug 2000 - Feb 2003

- Lead and coordinate equipment design and construction for new TV plant in Mexicali Mexico.
- Lead commissioning team consisting of automated equipment coordinate engineers, subcontractors, and resources during acceptance and all phases of project. Supervise installation, ensure process capability and start-up.
- Project management experience, program proposal, planning and execution for equipment and operation in new TV facility. Proficiency with earned-value, cost tracking and experience in leading a design project. Implement Six Sigma and Lean Manufacturing methodologies.

### **Project Manager, LG Electronics**

Jan 1998 - Jul 2000

- Project Management, manage cross-functional teams, product development scheduling for marketing entry, risk management, six sigma quality process for business operation cost reduction, customer- product support, manufacturing, and testing procedures.
- American product introduction program coordinator, study for new manufacturing equipment, logistics and projects for manufacturing television product.
- Responsible of TV manufacturing plant start-up and plants relocation in Reynosa Mexico / Mexicali product transfer, coordinating manufacturing facilities, materials logistics and resources.

# **Advance Manufacturing Engineer, ZENITH Electronics**

Jan 1996 - Dec1997

Mechanical design CAD/CAM in advanced electro-mechanical automation of electronics assembly lines.
 Design, justify, procure, technology research, automation, and robotic equipment for new production facilities.

#### **EDUCATION:**

MBA (Master of Business Administration).

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey; (ITESM) Monterrey, Mexico. April 1999

BSME, EE. Bachelor of Science in Mechanical & Electrical Engineering

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey; (ITESM) Monterrey, Mexico December 1995. **PMP, Project Management Certified,** Project Management Institute (PMI)

Languages: English, Spanish

Basic: German, Portuguese